What's in the box?
ما الذي يحويه الصندوق؟
Whatever it is must be pretty important,
أيًا كان، فلابد أنه مهم
because I've traveled with it, moved it,
لأني اصطحبته في سفري وتنقلاتي
from apartment to apartment to apartment.
من شقة إلى أخرى إلى أخرى
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Sound familiar?
معتادون على سماع ذلك؟
Did you know that we Americans
أتعلمون أننا الأمريكيون
have about three times the amount of space
لدينا ثلاثة أضعاف المساحة..
we did 50 years ago?
التي كانت لنا منذ 50 سنة؟
Three times.
ثلاثة أضعاف
So you'd think, with all this extra space,
قد تظنون أن هذه المساحة الزائدة
we'd have plenty of room for all our stuff.
توفر حيزًا لأمتعتنا
Nope.
كلا
There's a new industry in town,
فهناك صناعة جديدة في المدينة
a 22 billion-dollar, 2.2 billion sq. ft. industry:
كلفتنا 22 بليون دولار وتمتد على 2.2 بليون قدم مربع :
that of personal storage.
صناعة التخزين الشخصي
So we've got triple the space,
إذ بتنا نملك ثلاثة أضعاف المساحة
but we've become such good shoppers
لكننا احترفنا التسوق
that we need even more space.
لدرجة تجعلنا نحتاج مساحة أكبر
So where does this lead?
ما نتيجة ذلك؟
Lots of credit card debt,
مزيد من بطاقات الائتمان والديون
huge environmental footprints,
وشغل مساحة كبيرة
and perhaps not coincidentally,
وربما ليست مصادفة
our happiness levels flat-lined over the same 50 years.
أن مستويات السعادة راكدة طوال الـ 50 سنة الماضية
Well I'm here to suggest there's a better way,
أنا هنا لأقترح أسلوبًا أفضل
that less might actually equal more.
أشياء أقل قد تؤدي إلى معاني أكثر
I bet most of us have experienced at some point
أراهن أن معظمنا جرب..
the joys of less:
متعة الأقل:
college -- in your dorm,
في مسكن الكلية،
traveling -- in a hotel room,
في حجرة فندق أثناء السفر
camping -- rig up basically nothing,
في المخيم حيث لا تصطحب شيئًا
maybe a boat.
وربما في مركب
Whatever it was for you, I bet that, among other things,
أيًا كانت تجربتك، أراهن أنها..
this gave you a little more freedom,
أعطتك مزيدًا من الحرية
a little more time.
والوقت أيضًا
So I'm going to suggest
لذا أقترح أن
that less stuff and less space
أمتعة أقل في مساحة أصغر
are going to equal a smaller footprint.
تشغل حيزًا أصغر
It's actually a great way to save you some money.
وهو أسلوب رائع لتوفير المال
And it's going to give you a little more ease in your life.
يضفي على حياتك مزيدًا من الراحة
So I started a project called Life Edited at lifeedited.org
فبدأت مشروع "حياة منسقة" على lifeedited.org
to further this conversation
لطرح الفكرة بشكل أعمق
and to find some great solutions in this area.
والبحث عن حلول مناسبة
First up: crowd-sourcing my 420 sq. ft. apartment in Manhattan
أولاً: تحديد مصدر الزحام في شقتي بمانهاتن بمساحة 420 ق2
with partners Mutopo and Jovoto.com.
بمساعدة Mutopo و Jovoto.com
I wanted it all --
أردت كل شيء
home office, sit down dinner for 10,
مكتب وطاولة طعام لـ 10 أفراد
room for guests,
وغرفة للضيوف
and all my kite surfing gear.
ومكان لعدة ركوب الموج
With over 300 entries from around the world,
وبعد تفقد 300 اقتراح من حول العالم
I got it, my own little jewel box.
توصلت إلى الحل
By buying a space that was 420 sq. ft.
فبشراء مساحة 240 قدم مربع
instead of 600,
بدلاً من 600
immediately I'm saving 200 grand.
أوفر 200 ألف دولار
Smaller space is going to make for smaller utilities --
ومساحة أصغر تتطلب مرافق أقل
save some more money there,
مما يوفر مزيدًا من المال
but also a smaller footprint.
والحيز المطلوب أيضًا
And because it's really designed
ولأنه صمم خصيصًا
around an edited set of possessions -- my favorite stuff --
ليشمل ممتلكاتي الخاصة والمفضلة
and really designed for me,
وصمم من أجلي
I'm really excited to be there.
فأنا حقًا متحمسًا للعيش به
So how can you live little?
كيف يمكنك العيش في مساحة أصغر؟
Three main approaches.
ثلاثة أساليب أساسية
First of all, you have to edit ruthlessly.
أولاً: نسق الحاجيات دون رحمة
We've got to clear the arteries of our lives.
أي نظف شرايين حياتك
And that shirt that I hadn't worn in years?
فالتيشرت الذي لم ترتديه منذ سنوات..
It's time for me to let it go.
حان وقت التخلص منه
We've got to cut the extraneous out of our lives,
عليك التخلص من كل ما هو دخيل
and we've got to learn to stem the inflow.
وأن تتعلم كيف توقف التدفق
We need to think before we buy.
ولتفكر قبل أن تشتري
Ask ourselves,
اسأل نفسك:
"Is that really going to make me happier? Truly?"
"هل سيجعلني ذلك أكثر سعادة؟حقًا؟
By all means,
في كل الأحوال
we should buy and own some great stuff.
علينا أن نمتلك بعض الأمتعة الكبيرة
But we want stuff that we're going to love for years,
لكننا نريد ما يسعدنا لسنوات
not just stuff.
لا أيةٌ أمتعة
Secondly, our new mantra:
ثانيًا، تعويذتنا الجديدة:
small is sexy.
كل ما هو بسيط مثير
We want space efficiency.
علينا استغلال المساحة
We want things that are designed
وامتلاك الأمتعة المصممة
for how they're used the vast majority of the time,
لاستخدامها معظم الوقت
not that rare event.
لا في مناسبات محددة فقط
Why have a six burner stove
لم تمتلك موقدًا بـ 6 شعلات
when you rarely use three?
إن كنت لا تستخدم أكثر من 3؟
So we want things that nest,
نحتاج أشياء تتداخل
we want things that stack, and we want it digitized.
وتتراص، وأن نؤتمت العمل
You can take paperwork,
يمكنك جمع الأوراق
books, movies,
والكتب والأفلام
and you can make it disappear -- it's magic.
وإخفاءها من حياتك بلمسة سحرية
Finally, we want multifunctional spaces and housewares --
وأخيرًا، نحتاج مساحات وأدوات متعددة الاستخدام
a sink combined with a toilet,
حوض مع المرحاض
a dining table becomes a bed --
طاولة طعام تتحول لسرير
same space,
نفس المساحة
a little side table
منضدة جانبية صغيرة
stretches out to seat 10.
تُفتح لتسع 10 مقاعد
In the winning Life Edited scheme in a render here,
وضمن خطة "الحياة المنسقة" الناجحة
we combine a moving wall with transformer furniture
دمجنا حائطًا متحركًا مع أثاث متحول
to get a lot out of the space.
لاستغلال مزيد من المساحة
Look at the coffee table --
ها هي منضدة القهوة
it grows in height and width
تمتد طولاً وعرضًا
to seat 10.
لتشمل 10 مقاعد
My office folds away,
ومكتبي يمكن شده للخارج
easily hidden.
أو طيه بسهوله
My bed just pops out of the wall with two fingers.
والسرير يُفتح من الحائط بإصبعين
Guests? Move the moving wall,
الضيوف؟ حرك الحائط
have some fold-down guest beds.
لتجد الأسرة المطوية
And of course, my own movie theater.
وبالطبع شاشة السينما الخاصة بي
So I'm not saying that we all need to live
لا أزعم أن علينا العيش..
in 420 sq. ft.
في 420 قدم مربع
But consider the benefits of an edited life.
لكن علينا الانتباه إلى مزايا الحياة المنسقة
Go from 3,000 to 2,000,
لنخفض من 3000 إلى 2000
from 1,500 to 1,000.
ومن ثم من 1500 إلى 1000
Most of us, maybe all of us,
فمعظمنا، وربما جميعنا
are here pretty happily for a bunch of days
مستمتعون هنا ليومين
with a couple of bags,
مع حقيبتين فقط
maybe a small space, a hotel room.
وربما في حجرة فندق مساحتها صغيرة
So when you go home and you walk through your front door,
لذا حين تدخل منزلك وتفتح الباب
take a second and ask yourselves,
اسأل نفسك..
"Could I do with a little life editing?
"هل يمكنني تنسيق حياتي قليلاً؟"
Would that give me a little more freedom?
هل يمنحني ذلك مزيدًا من الحرية؟
Maybe a little more time?"
ويوفر لي الوقت؟"
What's in the box?
ما الذي يحويه الصندوق؟
It doesn't really matter.
لا يهم
I know I don't need it.
فأنا لا أحتاجه
What's in yours?
ما الذي يحويه صندوقك؟
Maybe, just maybe,
ربما، وهو مجرد احتمال
less might equal more.
أن الأقل يمنحنا الأكثر
So let's make room
لذا فلنوفر مساحة
for the good stuff.
للأمتعة النافعة
Thank you.
شكرًا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)